have you ever wondered about the
infinite sum shown here 1 4 plus 1 4
squared plus one-fourth cubed and so on
one way to make sense of this sum is to
start with an equilateral triangle and
decompose it into four equal pieces then
shade the middle triangle which
represents one-fourth of the area now do
the same thing with the upper triangle
and repeat over and over again each time
shading one-fourth of the remaining
upper triangle so that we're shading
powers of one-fourth
notice that the total shaded area in
this equilateral triangle can be
represented by the infinite sum of the
powers of one-fourth
but now here's the amazing trick this
process has divided the original
equilateral triangle into three pieces
which are all stacks of triangles at
each level the triangles are the same
size so we've divided the equilateral
triangle into three equal pieces
therefore the sum of the powers of
one-fourth is equal to one-third